

#### SAYED KHALIL

Kafr El-Sheikh | Egypt

(+2) 01010412509

(+2) 01114714335

Sayedsharm991@gmail.com

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree Faculty of Arts Tanta University

#### LANGUAGES

Arabic – Mother tongue
English – Excellent reading,
writing and speaking
Italian – Excellent reading,
writing and speaking
Russian – basic

# **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

- Ability to comply with all Food and Beverage brand standards
- Ability to work under pressure
- Able to meet financial targets
- Excellent grooming standards
- Willingness to develop team members
- Flexibility to respond to a range of different work situations
- Problem-Solving Skills
- Training and Leadership
- Team building
- Self-motivated
- Ability to multi-tasks

# EL SAYED KHALIL EL GAMMAL

**FOOD & BEVERAGE MANAGER** 

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Experienced Food and Beverage Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the hospitality industry. Skilled in Hospitality Management, Hotel Management. Within food and beverage management. A good motivator with team building skills, 20 years of experience in the hospitality industry with success at improving guest satisfaction and profit. capable of working within pressurized environment, meeting set targets and budgets, Able to communicate with people at all levels, using effective negotiating and coaching skills. Looking to further my career and try new challenges.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# FOOD & BEVERAGE MANAGER

2020 – June 2021

Sea Star Beau Rivage Hotel | Hurghada | Egypt 300 Rooms, 10 Outlets Reporting to: General Manager

# **Duties & Responsibilities:**

Managing operations of all food and beverage outlets to deliver an excellent guest and member experience. Manage, train, and develop team members and work within all budgeted guidelines. Responsible for performing the following tasks to the highest standards:

- Manage all Food and Beverage Outlet operations.
- Maintain exceptional levels of customer service.
- Ensure compliance of brand standards.
- Recruit, manage, train and develop the Food and Beverage team.
- Manage guest gueries in a timely and efficient manner.
- Work within budgeted guidelines in relation to Food, Liquor Costs and Payroll.
- Set departmental targets and objectives, work schedules, budgets, and policies and procedures.
- Develop menus with other members of Food and Beverage team.
- Incentivize team members to maximize sales and revenue.
- Evaluate guest satisfaction levels with a focus on continuous improvement.
- Ensure communication meetings are conducted and post-meeting minutes generated.
- Assist other departments wherever necessary and maintain good working relationships.
- Purchase and control of inventory.
- Monitors and maintains all outlet sanitation, storage and rotation of inventory.
- Monitor revenues and expenses to maximize sales.
- Negotiate with clients for use of facilities for catering, parties, banquets, etc.
- Comply with hotel security, fire regulations and all health and safety legislation.

## **FOOD & BEVERAGE MANAGER**

2016 – 2020

El Hayat Sharm Resort | Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt

212 Rooms, 8 Outlets

Reporting to: General Manager

Managing all F&B operations and for delivering an excellent guest experience. Plan and manage all F&B orders, staff and finance. Maximize sales and revenue through customer satisfaction and employee engagement.

- Manage all F&B and day-to-day operations within budgeted guidelines and to the highest standards.
- Preserve excellent levels of internal and external customer service.
- Design exceptional menus, purchase goods and continuously make necessary improvements.
- Identify customers' needs and respond proactively to all of their concerns.
- Lead F&B team by attracting, recruiting, training and appraising talented personnel Establish targets, schedules, policies and procedures.
- Provide a two-way communication and nurture an ownership environment with emphasis in motivation and teamwork.
- Comply with all health and safety regulations.
- Report on management regarding sales results and productivity.
- Proven food and beverage management experience.
- Working knowledge of various computer software programs (MS Office, restaurant management software, POS)
- Ability to spot and resolve problems efficiently.
- Mastery in delegating multiple tasks.
- Communication and leadership skills.
- Up to date with food and beverages trends and best practices.
- Ability to manage personnel and meet financial targets.
- Guest-oriented and service-minded.

## **ASST. F&B MANAGER**

2014 - 2016

El Hayat Sharm Resort | Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt

212 Rooms, 8 Outlets

Reporting to: General Manager

Assisting with managing operations of all Food and Beverage outlets to deliver an excellent Guest and Member experience. An Assistant Food and Beverage Manager will also be required to manage, train, and develop team members and work within all budgeted guidelines. Specifically, you will be responsible for performing the following tasks to the highest standards:

- Oversee operations of Food and Beverage outlets.
- Maintain exceptional levels of customer service.
- · Recruit, manage, train, and develop the team.
- Assist with annual and mid-year appraisals with team members under your responsibility.
- Manage guest gueries in a timely and efficient manner.
- Work within budgeted guidelines.
- Assist in setting departmental targets and objectives, work schedules, budgets, and policies and procedures.
- Develop menus with other members of Food and Beverage team.
- Accountable for monthly stock takes.
- Incentivize team members to maximize sales and revenue.
- Deputies for the Food and Beverage manager in their absence.
- Comply with hotel security, fire regulations and all health and safety legislation.
- Assist other departments wherever necessary and maintain good working relationships.

# **Restaurant Manager**

2010 - 2014

Gardenia Plaza Hotels & Resorts | Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt

432 ROOMS, 8 OUTLETS

Reporting to: Food & Beverage Manager

Handle the day-to-day operations of restaurant. Play a key role on teamwork by hiring, scheduling, and managing the restaurant staff as well as overseeing the success and profitability of the business.

- Recruit, train, supervise, and develop restaurant staff, including hosts, servers, cooks, bartenders, and dishwashers.
- Create employee schedules to ensure adequate staffing of the restaurant at all times.
- Handle paperwork and other administrative duties.
- Maintain stock levels and order supplies when necessary.
- Manage the budget and keep relevant statistical and financial records.
- Plan new restaurant menus. Address customer inquiries and complaints.
- Ensure that the restaurant complies with all necessary hygiene, health and safety, and licensing requirements and guidelines.
- Handle complaints, conflicts, questions, and suggestions from restaurant employees.

2009 - 2010 **Head Waiter** 

Tulip Beach Resort & Spa (Flash International) | Marsa Alam | Egypt 492 Rooms, 11 Outlets

- Supervises and coordinates activities of dining room personnel to serve food, assigns duties, workstations, and responsibilities to personnel and directs their performances.
- Inspects dining tables and work areas for cleanliness.
- Greets guests and shows them to dining tables.
- Filling out daily reports on the operations of the day.
- Requisitions supplies, such as glassware, china, and silverware.

Captain 2007 - 2009

**Sol Sharm Hotel** 

Sol Cyrene Hotel (Opening) Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt

214 + 207 Rooms, 12 Outlets

- Running of shifts in both restaurants and bars.
- Training of new staff.
- Setting up of restaurants.

# Asst. Captain & Waiter

2002 - 2007

**Nubian Village Hotel** (Flash International) Island Nubian Hotel (Opening) Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt 291 + 229 Rooms, 12 Outlets

- Providing excellent customer services that promote satisfaction.
- Greeting customers and presenting menu.
- Service of food and drinks.

## COMPUTER SKILLS

Microsoft Office, Internet, Micros POS

Micros - Fidelio Materials Control, Comsys, Micros - Fidelio Sales & Catering

# **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Achieved highest guest review awards in booking.com 2018
- Employee of the Month, Sol Hotels, November 2007.
- Introduced new goals setting for all staff for promotional purposes.
- Designed & implemented new menus, food & beverage promotions.
- Lowered food & beverage labor cost by implementing new training procedures for the staff, reducing staff turnover. Reducing absenteeism by having a good rapport & motivating the staff.

# **INTERESTS**

Science | Business Development | Marketing | Psychology | Innovations | Reading

## TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

### (2009) Train the trainers

**Major Theme:** Identifying training needs, job specifications vs. job descriptions the role of trainers in the management process. How to prepare the departmental trainers?

Level: Training Manager

## (2011) Food safety risk management "HACCP"

It is a scientific, socio-economic, economic, regulatory and regulatory system to ensure food safety through hazard analysis, whether biochemical or physical, and control of CCPS along the food chain

# (2011) Food & beverages skills development

Major theme: Training skills on F&B on how to increase the average spend per cover

Level: F&B trainers, F&B manager

#### (2014) Hospitality leadership skills development

American hotel & lodging educational institute

#### (2014) Occupational Safety and Health

**Major theme:** Local laws and regulations concerning (work accidents, social Insurance, labor law) prevention of work accident, environment protection, sanitation and hygiene, the role of the Health and Safety committee.

Level: All Health & Safety committee members

National Center for Occupational Safety and Health Studies and Business

#### REFERENCES

Mr. Namazi Mekawi | General Manager Sea Star Beau Rivage Hotel | Hurghada | Egypt +2 01005057057 | gm@seastarbeaurivage.com

Mr. Ahmed Elmanadily | General Manager El Hayat Sharm Resort | Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt +2 01001190215 | ahmedmanadily@yahoo.com

Mr. Mohamed Salem | HR Manager Gardenia Plaza Hotel & Resort | Sharm El-Sheikh | Egypt +2 01001700319 | Hr@gardeniaplazahotel.com

All above certificates are available upon request Great honor to be a member in your teamwork

Sayed Khalil